Guide to the Stanford University, Office of Management and Budget, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of Management and Budget, records
1975-1984
SC0341
Stanford University. Office of Management and Budget.
Stanford University. Office of Planning and Management
16.5 Linear feet
Collection includes committee materials, plans, reports, and other documents pertaining to accessibility for the handicapped at Stanford, 1977-82; and memoranda, correspondence, financial records, reports, clippings, articles, and occasional drawings from specific building projects, 1975-84, including academic buildings, student and faculty housing, research facilities, the medical center, Memorial Church, equestrian facilities, statuary, athletic facilities, child care centers, golf course and club house, and many others.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1987.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes committee materials, plans, reports, and other documents pertaining to accessibility for the handicapped at Stanford, 1977-82; and memoranda, correspondence, financial records, reports, clippings, articles, and occasional drawings from specific building projects, 1975-84, including academic buildings, student and faculty housing, research facilities, the medical center, Memorial Church, equestrian facilities, statuary, athletic facilities, child care centers, golf course and club house, and many others.
Access Terms
Research Animal Facility (Stanford, Calif.); Stanford University. Office of Management and Budget.; Barrier-free design--United States.; People with disabilities--Services for--California.; Universities and colleges--Planning.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1986-131
  - Accessibility documents, 1977-1982
    - Committee on Handicapped (Box 1)
    - Implementation of Accessibility Transition Plan (funding) (Box 1)
    - Developing an Accessible Campus for the Handicapped (Box 1)
    - Higher Education Facilities. Facilities Planning and Management manuals (Box 1)
    - Transition Plan Notes & Ideas (rough drafts 1977-78) (Box 1)
    - Committee on Handicapped Book 2, 3, 4 (Box 1)
    - Analysis of Facilities for the Physically Handicapped at Stanford University (Box 1)
    - Summary of Efforts to Provide Program Access for the Handicapped at Stanford University (as of Dec. 1979) (Box 1)
    - Information on: employment, residential education, medical center, DAPER (Box 1)
  - Accessibility documents, 1987-1982
    - Implementation of Accessibility Transition Plan (vol. 1) (Box 2)
    - Transition Plan notes & Ideas & Ideas (rough drafts 1977-78) (Box 2)
    - Identification of Architectural Barriers and Other Environmental Hazards to Physically Disabled People, UC Berkeley, Vol. 1, 2 and 3 (Box 2)
  - Facilities
    - Cardiovascular Research Building July 1980, January 1981, April 1982 (Box 2)
    - Research Animal Facility Implementation Plan (Box 2)
    - Existing Research Animal Facilities (Box 2)
    - Boswell Clinic Report (Box 2)
    - Psychiatric Adaptive Reuse Feasibility Study (Box 2)
    - Hazardous Materials Control Program (Box 2)
    - Bldg. 120 May 1982 Bd. of Trustees materials (Box 2)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1988-097
  - 01-General, 1 & 10 space arrangements (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 01-120 Sociology (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 01-120 Sociology – reconstruction 1982- (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 01-120 Sociology – reconstruction 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 01-160 Political Science (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 01-170 History (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 01-460 Margaret Jacks Hall, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 01-500 Memorial Church roof (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 01-500 Memorial Church roof (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 01-500 1-500 Memorial Church organ 1981-82 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 02-210 Braun (design) 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 02-210 I Braun (design) 1981 (Box 3)
  - 02-210 II Braun (design) 1981 (Box 3)
  - 02-210 Braun 1982 (Box 3)
  - 02-210 Braun 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 02-210 Braun 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 02-300 Tresidder Memorial Union 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 04-250 High Energy Physics Lab (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 04-490 McCullough (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 04-490 McCullough (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 04-490 McCullough (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 04-490 McCullough (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 04-490 McCullough 1982/83 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 04-490 McCullough 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 07-220 Keck 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 07-220 Keck 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 07-220 Keck (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 07-220 Keck, Rudolph & Sletten meeting minutes (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 07-220 Postmortem meeting (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 07-220 Keck, The Move (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 07-220 Keck, Furniture (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 07-220 Keck (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 14-810 Red Barn (Oct. 1982-) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 14-810 Red Barn – Stables 1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 14-810 Red Barn – Stables 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 14-900 Meyer-Buck Estate (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 14-995 Ventura Hall (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1989-061
  - none GPI [General Plan Improvements] policy, 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 02-100 Bowman Alumni House, 1978-82 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 02-520/550 Renovation, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 02-590 Remodeling, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 02-600 Women’s Clubhouse, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 02-917 Owen House – Sociology space problem, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 40612 Cummings Art Building – everything, 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 18323 CPPC remodel, 1980-82 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 03-200 Green Library, 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 03-300 Cubberly Auditorium Renovation, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 18354 Ventura relocation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 25659 Center for Integrated Systems, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 04-520 Physics Undergraduate Center, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 05-200 Florence Moore Hall, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 05-350 Boathouse Study, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 05-900/910 Child Care, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 12-xxx Site 505, 1981 (Box 1)
  - 12-xxx Site 515, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 12-xxx Site 522, 1981 (Box 1)
  - 12-600 Satellite Lab Animal Compound, 1980-82 (Box 1)
  - 12-650 SSRL various projects, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 12-700 Jasper Ridge, 1980-82 (Box 1)
  - 12-917 Page Mill Quarry, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 12-918 Page Mill Machine Shop, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 13-10 Mausoleum, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 13-12 Angel of Grief, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 13-170 Print Shop (SUMC), 1970 (Box 1)
  - 13-900T Family Focus Temperature Building (SUMC), 1978 (Box 1)
  - 14-xxx General, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 14-xxx SCIP & RLIN moves to Jordan Quad, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 14-xxx Facilities- Ventura Hall Relocation, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 14-100 Central Steam & Chilled water plant, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 14-110 Cedar Hall, 1980-82 (Box 1)
  - 14-160 Jordan Quad, 1978-81 (Box 1)
  - 14-170 Pine Hall, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 14-200 George Forsythe Hall, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 14-550 Butler building, 1981 (Box 1)
  - 14-640 ESF funding, 1981 (Box 1)
  - 14-640 ESF incineration, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 14-xxx Incinerator planning, 1981-82 (Box 1)
  - 14-830 Red Barn Stables, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 14-810 Red Barn Stables, 1980-82 (Box 1)
  - 14-905T Dendral Modular, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 14-940T Oak, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 90-100 Hopkins Marine Station – general, 1980-82 (Box 1)
  - 90-140 Hopkins Marine Station Monterey Boat Works, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 90-180T Hopkins Marine Station Stockroom, 1977 (Box 1)
  - 90-909 800 Welch Rd. Rental (Blood Bank), 1982 (Box 1)
  - 90-400 Board of Trustees – 600 California, SF, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 90-932 Palo Alto Storage Warehouse, 1979-80 (Box 1)
  - 90-xxx Searsville Lake Leasehold, 1979-80 (Box 1)
  - 90-xxx SLAC: Single Pass Collider Ring, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 02-930 Serra House relocation, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 40603 Stanford Art Gallery, 1980-81 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 20149 Clock Bell Tower, 1981-82 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 02-910T Board of Trustees Modular, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 02-916 Mariposa House, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 02-921 Storey House, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 21947 Kresge Auditorium, 1979-82 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 02-140 Kingscote Gardens, 1970-81 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 02-210 Irvine Visit (Braun), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 02-500 Terman Engineering Lab, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 02-560 Reprographic Services, 1981-82 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 02-570 High Temperature Gas Dynamics Lab, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 02-580 Student Services, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 02-610 Mechanical Engineering, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 02-630 Stanford University Public Services, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 02-xxx General, 1972-82 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 40575 Post Office, 1975-82 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 40594 Center for Educational Research (CERAS), 1981-82 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 40594 Center for Educational Research (CERAS), 1980-81 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 18295 Crown Law Quad, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 03-300 Education (Cubberly Auditorium), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 03-300 Education (Cubberly Auditorium), 1982, 6/1 – 6/30 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 03-300 Education (Cubberly Auditorium), 1982, 7/1 – 9/30 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 03-300 Education (Cubberly Auditorium), 1982, 1/1 – 5/26 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 03-300 Cubberly Auditorium 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 03-200 Green Library, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 03-100 Hoover Tower Fire Safety, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 03-100 Hoover Tower Fire Safety, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 06-xxx General, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 06-xxx Controllers Office, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 04-700 Terman Engineering Library, 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 04-920T Dendral Modular Bldg., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 04-970T Petroleum Research Institute, 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 05-xxx General – Lagunita Lake, 1978-80 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 05-xxx General – Felt Lake, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 05-xxx New Student Housing, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 40673 Lagunita Court, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 05-100 Roble Hall, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 05-300 Knoll, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 05-410 Theta Delta Chi, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 05-420 Faculty Residence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 05-440 Sigma Alpha Epsilon, 1979-81 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 05-510 Lake House, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 05-630 Lake Lagunita, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 05-800 Golf Driving Range, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 05-920 Music Library Annex, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 04-350 Applied Electronics Lab, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 04-500 Physics Lecture Hall, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 04-540 Durand Bldg., 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 04-550 Skilling Auditorium, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 04-560 Mitchell Bldgs. Earth Sciences, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 04-560 Mitchell Bldgs. – Mechanical systems, 1978-80 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 04-710 Terman Engineering Center, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 25659 Center for Integrated Systems, 1978-80 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 04-150 Serra House, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 04-200 Ginzton Laboratories (Applied Physics), 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 04-300 Electronics Research Lab, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 18354 Ventura Relocation, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 25659 Center for Integrated Systems, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 07-10/20/30 East Medical Science Bldg. 1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 07-335 Research Animal Facility, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 07-335 Research Animal Facility, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 06-400 Wilbur Hall, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 06-600/650 Manzanita Park & Laundry Facility, 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 06-910T/920T Office of Development, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 07-330 Research Animal Facility, 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 06-xxx Development Office, 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 06-xxx Economics Department, 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 06-xxx Real Estate & Land Development, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 14763 Encina Commons, 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 18415 Eating Clubs, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 06-300/350 Crothers & Crothers Memorial Halls, 1979-80 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - none Meyer Library, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 03-210 New Library, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 07-320 Cardiovascular Research Center, 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 07-xxx Cardiovascular Center, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 07-400 Falconer Library – Biological Sciences, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 07-520/525 Sherman Fairchild Building & Auditorium, 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 08-110 DAPER Fieldhouse, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 08-200 Old Pavilion, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 08-300 Memorial Hall, 1979-82 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 08-300 Memorial Hall Advisory Group, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 08-320 Tanner Fountain, 1977-79 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 08-350 Business Graduate School, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 08-350 Business Graduate School, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 08-350 Business Graduate School, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 07-100 Museum elevator, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 07-100 Museum, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 07-100 Museum South Rotunda II, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 07-200 Chemistry, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 07-250T Old Chemistry Flammable Interim Storage, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 07-250 Organic Chemistry, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 07-260 Stauffer I, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 07-270 Stauffer II Physical Engineering, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 07-270+ Stauffer I, II, III Fume Hoods, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 07-290 Stauffer III chemical Engineering, 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 07-300 Medical Center Clinics Renovation Project, 1978-80 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 07-300 Medical Center, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 07-300 Biochemistry Expansion, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 07-300 Medical Center West Campus Science corp. yard, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 07-300 Medical Center Newborn Nursery, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 07-300 Radiobiology Research Bldg., 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 07-300 Radiobiology Expansion, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 07-300 Whitehead Institute, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 07-305 Boswell Clinics, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 07-309 Edwards Building (Medical Center), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 07-310 Hospital Modernization Project, 1977-82 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 07-550 Louis B. Mayer Cancer Biology Research Lab, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 07-930T Stanford Primate Faculty, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 07-970T Koko’s House, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 07-995T Modulars for Division of Laboratory Animal Medicine, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - 07-997T Chemical Waste Interim Facility, 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - 08-xxx Encina Pools, 1979-80 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 08-100 Athletics & P.E. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 08-xxx Memorial Auditorium Seating Analysis, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 11-160 Hurlburt House, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 10-300 Bing Nursery School, 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 10-145 Escondido V High rise Mirrielees, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 10-119 Escondido IV High rise Quillen, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 27303 Escondido II High rise Barnes, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 40817 Escondido Village I, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 09-945T Peninsula Sanitary Service Inc., 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 09-040T Telecommunications Office Space, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 09-931 Centralization of Procurement, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 09-580 Concession Stand, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 09-385 Varsity Tennis Facility, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 09-xxx DAPER – Tennis & Golf Scoreboards, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 09-310 De Guerre Pools & Courts, 1979-81 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 09-300 Maples Pavilion, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 09-190 Telecommunications Center, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 09-145 Hazardous Storage Bldg., 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 09-140 Custodial Office, 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 09-120 Credit Union, Stanford Federal, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 09-110 Stores: 330 Bonair Siding, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 09-100 Plant Service Bldg., 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 09-105 Utilities Department Office Space, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 08-990T Personnel Modular Bldg., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 08-980T Peter Coutts Housing Trailer, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 08-600 Frost Amphitheatre, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 08-500 Galvez House, 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 08-400 Old Steam Plant, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 08-360 Graduate School of Business, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 25903 Student Observatory I, 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 40907 Lathrop Gate House, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 40887 Golf Club House, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - 12-150 D. C. Power Building, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 12-xxx General, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 11-330 Hanna (F. L. Wright) Residence thru Maintenance PJT & Hobby House, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 11-310 Synergy House, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - 11-270 Phi Kappa Psi, 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 11-260 Durand House, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - 11-250 Gardiner Apartments, 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - 11-240 Jordan Co-op, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - 11-230 Guthrie House, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - 11-200 Grove II (Mayfield), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - 11-130 Huston House, 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - 10-350 SCRA (Rec. Assoc.) Administration, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - 11-xxx Peter Coutts Hill, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - 11-xxx Row House – General, 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - 11-130 Huston House – smoke detector, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - 02-050 Crown Law School Student Center, 1983-84 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 07-400/410 Herrin Labs, 1980-82 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 05-xxx New Student Housing, 1981(June – Dec.) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 05-xxx New Student Housing, 1981 Jan. – May) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 05-xxx New Student Housing, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 05-xxx Committee on Student Residence – energy consultant (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - none Boystown Center, 1979-80 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - none Boystown Center, 1976-80 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - none Boystown Center, 1975-76 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 14-640 Environmental Safety Facility, 1983 Sept.-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 14-640 Environmental Safety Facility, 1983 July-Aug. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 14-640 Environmental Safety Facility, 1983 Feb.-June (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 14-640 Environmental Safety Facility, 1983 Jan. (Box 7, Folder 13)